Hello friends, welcome to Insights.
In today's video, we are going to talk about what happens when
we get admitted to a hospital for
treatment.
Even though it is a network hospital, the insurance company does
not give a cashless claim and says that
we cannot give you a cashless claim. You should
submit your bill in reverse. We will
not approve this claim as cashless by mentioning some such letter
and they deny the claim as cashless
and ask you to submit it in reverse. So
why do insurance companies say this? Are there any reasons? Are there any
reasons? I am going to
tell you about that in this video. So, please
watch the video till the end. We are going to discuss it in full detail.
So, before starting the video,
please subscribe to the channel and
like the video. So let's start the video.
[Music]
Whenever we get admitted to a network hospital for treatment, the
insurance company rejects our claim
and says that
we cannot give you a cashless claim. You should
submit your bill in reverse and we will
approve the claim.  What needs to be done in this situation is
that we have to collect our
final hospital bills, discharge summary
receipt, or medicine
bills at the
time of discharge.
Later, we have to fill out reimbursement forms A and B and
send them to the insurance company's endorsement.
I have made a separate video about the investment process, you
can watch it. In this video, I am going to explain
why insurance companies refuse to provide cashless treatment. Many times,
we don't face so much trouble that we need to be
admitted, but what happens is that
after having an insurance card, we feel that if we have the card,
our treatment should be free.
We say the same thing in the hospital, so the
hospital also admits the patient keeping this in mind. They do
n't care whether they will get cashless treatment or not,
they are only concerned with their payment. So, even
if the insurance company denies them or
rejects their case,
they will accept the cash payment as well;
they have no problem, but  If the
policy holder faces a problem, then the
policy holder has to think that he needs to be
admitted genuinely, he has a
problem in the sense that he needs to be admitted,
he has a problem, only then he should use his health
card, for his
treatment one should
not get admitted for a normal problem, in order to save a few bucks one has to pay a lot of
money, which causes
loss to you only, secondly when the
insurance company finds out that the
claim is baseless,
it refuses to give cashless treatment
because there is a team of doctors there too,
when the hospital team sends the treatment
related documents to the insurance company, then there is a
team of doctors there
who check those documents, if
they feel that this patient did
not need to be admitted to the hospital, then they deny the claim,
reject it
and say that you should put your bill
in reimbursement because they feel that the
patient was not fit to be admitted and whatever the reasons may be, it may be due to the
hospital
or the patient's attendance, the patient
Whatever may be the reason for admission, they
ask to pay the amount later in the investment, so in that condition we have to collect
all the documents like final bill, discharge summary and receipt etc.
from the hospital,
after that we have to attach it with the form and
send it to the insurance company
that if you have not received the claim in cashless then
you will also not get it, you should
fill in your problem properly and send it, after taking the required
time send the documents and you will
get it, that's all in today's video, if you liked the video then
like it and subscribe to the channel, if you have
any question then
write it in the comment section, I will
answer it, see you
in the next video, till then hello